

Mashhood Qadeer

Senior IOS Developer (SwiftUI, UIKit, Objective-c)

Hello, I have a passion for creating innovative and user-friendly ios apps. Over 5 years of professional experience, I have honed my skills in Swift and Objective-C to deliver quality iOS solutions for health, finance and entertainment domains. You will find me a valuable resource to deliver work before deadlines and according to your asked standards.

+923066791838

mas7ga387@gmail.com in www.linkedin.com/in/mgadeer87

SKILLS & COMPETENCIES

Layout Designing	Languages	Data Driven
Storyboard Programmatic Adaptive Layouts IBDesignable Custom Layouts	SwiftUI Swift Objective-C	Core data Realm UserDefaults Keychain
API Integration	Interactive Content	Framework Management
REST APIs (JSON) SOAP (XML)	Core Animations SceneKit	Podspec SPM Carthage
Code Quality	Version Control	CI/CD
Unit Testing X-swift Format SwiftLint SonarQube	Git	FastLane

WORK EXPERIENCE



Senior IOS developer

Rawalpindi, Pakistan (2021- Present)

Projects Developed in: Swift, Swift-UI, Objective-C

Key Responsibilities:

- Developed most recent Companion app revamping to merge CareCloud Companion app to talklite serving both environment users and developed with speed to deliver it within 3 sprints. App have adaptive layouts to support iPhone and iPad devices.
- Developed Expense reporting ios app for company finance department to get employee's expense transactions for Amex Card, employees personal card and Mileage transactions. I developed this app as a sole IOS developer working closely with web service team members. App have MapKit, custom views to match 100% design given by designers, remote notification handling and background fetches.
- Developed Anesthesia IOS application as a sole IOS developer. App have challenging layout and custom views to show very complex interactive graphs like for operation monitoring to show the oxygen flow where each cell is growing along with horizontal axis and same values cells merged to one while others remain there. It's developed for the iPad and acts as a mini iEHR app.
- Worked on the existing app of the company with other team members to add features to talkCheckin for custom forms, Peads form, Sick visit flows updates, updated many screens and added new features.



Developed many POC apps for the company to add features to existing apps for **BLE enabled** communication for omron bp monitor with ios synching data to the webservice. Healthkit integration with existing apps to fetch users health data.



IOS developer

Faisalabad, Pakistan (2018- 2021) Projects Developed in: Swift

Key Responsibilities:

- Developed company core app Invitation Maker which is a mini template editor to create invitation cards. It was a very challenging job to make algo for template psd to editable tree of views in swift. I worked on backend as well using node js to parse psd to db I used psd parser npm and handled that job. Used AVFoundation to mix audios and a lot of stuff to provider editor undo and redo.
- Developed mosque finder app from scratch to complete production for the company for the UK based audience. App have Agora io sdk integration for video calling. Living voice from mosque using subject based notification subscriptions in firebase. Local data storage for offline read support using Realm.

Education & Languages

Education	Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science (2014-2018)
Languages	EnglishHindi

I hereby affirm that the above information is true and correct to the best of my knowledge.